# Parsa Khayatzadeh | Resume

pk525@cornell.edu

Ph.D. Student in Systems Engineering, Cornell University:

Supervisior:: Prof. Michael Charles

Research Area: Computational Sustainability Techs: IAMs, Human-Earth Systems, Julia, R  $Ithaca, \ NY$  parsakhay.com/research

## Summary

I have started my Ph.D. at Cornell as a Systems Engineering student under the supervision of Prof. Michael Charles. I am interested in design aspect of human-earth models. I link different modules of the system to provide a narrative of plausible futures of the world. My current research focuses on the downscaled study of IAMs aimed to serve tribal governed communities and my case study is Navajo Nation.

#### Education

Ph.D. in Systems Engineering - Ithaca, NY

Aug. 2023 - Current

• Area: Computational Sustainability

 $\mathbf{B}.\mathbf{Sc}.$  in Industrial Engineering - Tehran, Iran

Aug. 2018 - Jul. 2022

- Thesis: PV vs. CSP: a solar renewable technology review and electricity cost analysis based on improvised LCOE
- Course Highlights: Operations Research System Analysis Engineering Statistics Fundamentals of Probability Microeconomic Theory Macroeconomics Statistical Quality Control Decision Analysis

### Academic Experience

Teaching Assistant - Cornell University

Aug. 2024 - Dec. 2024

- Professor: Natalie Cápiro
- Engineering Processes for Environmental Sustainability

Teaching Assistant - University of Tehran

Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2022

• Courses: Simulation Principles - Probability and Applications - Microeconomics - Macroeconomics - System Analytics

Board Member - Scientific Association of Industrial Engineering, University of Tehran (UTIESA)

Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2021

- (Oliban)
- Developing new methods to analyze social networks
- $\bullet$  Implementing methods in libraries
- Gathering and analyzing large datsets from Social Media APIs

#### Extracurricular Activities

University of Tehran - Aug. 2019 - Jul. 2021

- Board Member of Scientific Association of Industrial Engineering at University of Tehran (UTIESA)
- Managing Editor of Fankaav Stident Journal
- Award: Harekat, University's best student journal in 2022